minestatus.net 2016-04-23

# Privacy Policy | Minecraft Servers List - Minestatus.net

**Date of Last Revision: March 23, 2012**

We collect only the following information from the use of Minestatus. We never sell your personal information to third parties. If you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy policy, please contact [privacy@minestatus.net](mailto:privacy@minestatus.net). 

### Data We Collect

**Information you provide to us:**

**Contact Information.** When you register on Minestatus, you are asked for your email address. This email is used for notices, confirmation of the email, password retrieval, and account unlocking. 

**Server Information.** When you add a server onto Minestatus, you consent us to publicly display the server's connection information, such as it's address and port. 

**Personally Identifying Information (PII).** When you sign up for a premium service, we may collect more information about you which includes but is not limited to: your name, address, phone number, and payment information. When you terminate your account this information is deleted from Minestatus' databases. 

**Information we collect when you access Minestatus:**

**Access Information.** When you visit Minestatus from a computer, mobile phone, or any other device, information is collected that includes your browser type, location, IP address, and as well as any pages you visit. 

**Cookies.** We use cookies to store session information of your account. This allows us to keep you logged in to Minestatus. You can remove and disable cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. However, keep in mind that this may cause you to be unable to login to your account on Minestatus. 

**Third Party Advertisements.** Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).  

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>. 

### How We Use This Information

**To manage the service.** We use the information that we collect to provide services, to measure the traffic flow, to statistically track traffic through out the site, to prevent illegal activities, and to enforce the Terms of Service. 

**To contact you.** We may from time to time email you regarding notices relating to Minestatus and your account. 

**To track your server statistically.** We use the information on your server in order to track the server's uptime and share player data if applicable. 

**To complete a transaction.** We use PII in order to complete a payment transaction for a premium service. This may be shared with third-parties if necessary to complete the transaction. 

### How You Can Change or Remove Information

**Editing your account information.** You may change your account information at any time by going to "Account Settings". 

**Editing your server information.** You may change the server information such as the name, banner, address, port, and description by going to your server's page and clicking "Edit" at the bottom. Additionally, a server can be deleted by clicking "Delete" at the bottom of the server. 

**Deleting your account.** If you no longer wish to use Minestatus, you may delete your account. This can be done by going to "Account Settings" and clicking "delete your account" at the bottom. This will remove any of your servers that you are listed as the last owner on. 

**Backup copies.** Removed and deleted information may exist in backup copies, but they will not be available to others. 

### Other Terms

**Changes.** Minestatus reserves the right to change the Privacy Policy at anytime with or without notice. 

**Consent to Collection and Processing in the United States.** You agree by using Minestatus you consent to having your personal information transferred to and processed in the United States. 

**Definitions.** "We," "us," "you" mean the same as defined in the Terms of Service.
